

About me

I am a passionate and dedicated researcher in Biomedical Engineering, currently working on Explainable Artificial Intelligent algorithms for assisting Ovarian Cancer treatment.

I regard myself smiling, respectful, ambitious and fast-learner.

Outside of work, I am strongly passionate about sport and travelling, always searching for new fast-paced experiences.

Contacts

(k) +39 393 1860169

☑ ff.francescafati@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/francesca-fati

https://github.com/FrancescaFati

Skills

Digital

Programming/IT: Python, C++, C, MATLAB, Git, JavaScript Al: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, SciKit Engineering: ROS Hardware: Microcontrollers

Office: LaTeX, Microsoft Office Suite

Language

Italian: Native speaker English: TOIEC Level B2, 2020.

This CV was last updated on September 23th 2024.

I authorize the processing of personal data according to EU Regulation 679/2016 or according to the reader's local regulations if not in the EU.

francisco fel

Clicking will open a research paper Clicking will open my github profile

Francesca Fati

Researcher in Biomedical Engineering

Milan, Italy
Date of birth: 27th October 1997

Working Experience

Collaborator in the Divsion of Surgical Gynecology IEO

November 2023 - in progress | European Institute of Oncology (IEO) | Milan, IT Project: "Under-XAI" - Understanding Ovarian Cancer initiation and progression thorugh explainable AI. Project code: PNRR-MAD-2022-12376574.

Webpage: https://nearlab.polimi.it/underxai/

Internship at NeuroEngineering and Medical Robotics Laboratory

June 2023 - October 2023 | Politecnico di Milano | Department of Electronics, Information and Bioengineering | Milan, IT

Website: https://nearlab.polimi.it/medical/

Au pair

January 2020 - June 2020 | St. Albans, London, UK

Education

Phd in Biomedical Engineering

September 2023 - in progress | Politecnico di Milano

MSc in Biomedical Engineering, 110/110 cum laude

September 2020 - May 2023 | Politecnico di Milano, IT

Thesis: "Hybrid Model for a tendon-driven steerable catheter for minimally invasive

Mitral valve repair " at NEARLab. Supervisor: Prof. Elena De Momi.

BSc in Biomedical Engineering, 110/110

September 2016 - October 2019 | Università di Genova, IT Thesis: "Algorithm for clustering analysis in neural networks". Supervisor: Prof. Marco Storace.

Publications

Deep learning-based tumor resectability prediction model in patients with Ovarian Cancer: a preliminary evaluation

Fati F., Rosanu M., De Vitis L., Schivardi G., Multinu F., Veraldi R., Zaffino P., Cosentino C., Spadea M., De Momi E.

Ital-IA 2024. 2024.

Optimizing Heart Valve Surgery with Model-Free Catheter Control

Bicchi A., **Fati F.**, Quacquarelli M., Votta E., De Momi E.

Hamlyn Symposium on Medical Robotics 2023.

Reproducing a decision-making network in a virtual visual discrimination task \square

Trapani A., Sheiban F., Bertone E., Chiosso S., Colombo L., D'Andrea M., De Santis F., **Fati F.**, Fossati V., Gonzalez V., Pedrocchi A.

Frontier in Integrative Neuroscience 2022.

Relevant Works O

E-health Methods and Applications

Implementation of a comprehensive Alexa skill to support the rehabilitation of stroke patients, promoting adherence and providing various memory exercises.

Medical Robotics and Technologies for computer aided surgery laboratory

Implementation of a deep learning approach for cystoscopy/ureteroscopy tumours segmentation to recognize lesions/tumors in images of the urinary tract during

endoscopic surgery.